Guide to the Royal College of Art Sketch Club Collection
Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
- Eric C. Gregory letter to Evelyn Hunt, 1937 October 4; Gregory, Eric, 1887-1959; 1 sheet (1 page): typed letter, signed; 26 x 18 cm (Box 1, Folder 28)
  Gregory agrees to present a prize, though asks about the exact conditions, noting past response has been small. He says he is open to modifications, and suggests Hunt speak to Mr. Bawden [i.e., Edward Bawden?]. Written at the bottom, in pencil: "Gave general, book jackets."
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Gregory, Eric, 1887-1959 -- Correspondence; Hunt, Evelyn Janet, 1914-2001 -- Correspondence; Bawden, Edward, 1903-1989
- Eric C. Gregory letter to Evelyn Hunt, 1937 October 12; Gregory, Eric, 1887-1959; 1 sheet (1 page): typed letter, signed; 26 x 18 cm (Box 1, Folder 29)
  Gregory agrees to Hunt's (unspecified) suggestion, and says she should carry out whatever is left to be done.
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Gregory, Eric, 1887-1959 -- Correspondence; Hunt, Evelyn Janet, 1914-2001 -- Correspondence
- Eric C. Gregory letter to Evelyn Hunt, 1937 November 11; Gregory, Eric, 1887-1959; 1 sheet (1 page): typed letter, signed; 26 x 18 cm (Box 1, Folder 30)
  Gregory discusses times when he will be in London, and says he will call Hunt.
- Evelyn F. Hall letter to unidentified recipient, 1936; Hall, Evelyn F.; 1 sheet (1 page): typed letter; 14 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 31)
  Hall lists the officers of the "Association of Students' Sketch Clubs" and invites the recipient to submit work to the association's next exhibit in February of 1937. Written at the top of the page is: "We have nothing to do with this, but they will write every other week."
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Hall, Evelyn F. -- Correspondence
- William Smith, Viscount Hambleden (secretary of) letter to Evelyn Hunt, 1937 October 8; Hambleden, William Smith, Viscount, 1903-1948; 1 sheet (1 page): typed letter, signed; 26 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 32)
  The letter conveys Lord Hambleden's interest in seeing the exhibition, and mentions an enclosed five guineas as a prize.
  Letterhead: "31, Belgrave Square, London, S.W.1."
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Hambleden, William Smith, Viscount, 1903-1948 -- Correspondence; Hunt, Evelyn Janet, 1914-2001 -- Correspondence
- Martin Hardie letter to J. Anthony Denney, 1935 July 11; Hardie, Martin, 1875-1952; 1 sheet (1 page): typed letter, signed; 25 x 19 cm (Box 1, Folder 33)
  Hardie agrees to give a prize for the same amount as in the previous year, and he leaves it to the Committee to decide the award will be for.
  Letterhead: "Victoria & Albert Museum, South Kensington, S.W.7., Dept. of Paintings, Dept. of Engraving, Illustration, & Design"
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Hardie, Martin, 1875-1952 -- Correspondence; Denney, Anthony, 1913-1990 -- Correspondence
- George Ravensworth Hughes letter to Margaret Kaye, 1936 August 4; Hughes, George Ravensworth; 1 sheet (1 page): typed letter, signed; 26 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 34)
  Hughes writes that it will be difficult to get a decision on providing a prize for the exhibit this year, but that he will make an effort to see the show and discuss future possibilities then. Hand-written at the bottom: "write early - will give prize. K."
  Blind-embossed seal; letterhead: "Goldsmiths' Hall, Foster Lane, Cheapside, London E.C.2. Telephone National 6036"
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Hughes, George Ravensworth -- Correspondence; Kaye, Margaret, 1912-2002 -- Correspondence
- Letter from unidentified author to Joseph Jago, 1934 October 14; 1 sheet (1 page): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 18 cm (Box 1, Folder 35)
  The author (whose signature is illegible) asks "When do you want me to select the textile to which I give my prize …"
  Letterhead: "The Studio. 27, Holland Park Avenue. W.11."
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Jago, Joseph -- Correspondence
- E. McKnight Kauffer letter to Frank B. Mason, 1934 December 4; Kauffer, E. McKnight (Edward McKnight), 1890-1954; 1 sheet (1 page): typed letter, signed; 26 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 36)
  Kauffer informs Mason he has gotten [E.C.] Gregory's consent to donate a prize for the exhibition, and will himself present the prize. He also mentions the probable willingness of Denis Cohen to offer a prize as well. Marginalia at bottom of page in pencil, signed FBM, notes that he verified Gregory's intent to provide a prize.
  Letterhead: "From E McKnight Kauffer 141 Swan Court Chelsea London SW3 Flaxman 0217"
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Kauffer, E. McKnight (Edward McKnight), 1890-1954 -- Correspondence; Mason, Frank B. -- Correspondence; Gregory, Eric, 1887-1959; Cohen, Dennis, 1891-1970
- E. McKnight Kauffer letter to Evelyn Hunt, 1937 October 23; Kauffer, E. McKnight (Edward McKnight), 1890-1954; 1 sheet (1 page): typed letter, signed; 26 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 37)
  Kauffer accepts the invitation to act as adjudicator for the exhibition and asks for details regarding time.
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Kauffer, E. McKnight (Edward McKnight), 1890-1954 -- Correspondence; Hunt, Evelyn Janet, 1914-2001 -- Correspondence
- E. McKnight Kauffer letter to Evelyn Hunt, 1937 November 6; Kauffer, E. McKnight (Edward McKnight), 1890-1954; 1 sheet (1 page): typed letter, signed; 28 x 19 cm (Box 1, Folder 38)
  Kauffer confirms intention to see exhibit on Friday 19 in the afternoon.
  Letterhead: "E. McKnight Kauffer Hon. R.D.I. 141 Swan Court Chelsea S.W.3 Flaxman 0217"
- Alexander Korda letter to Margaret Kaye, 1936 September 8; Korda, Alexander, Sir, 1893-1956; 1 sheet (1 page): typed letter, signed; 26 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 39)
  Korda expresses his gratitude for the offer to open the Students' Group exhibition but, as he will be away "for the purpose of making shots in a picture," he cannot accept.
  Letterhead includes larger image of Big Ben, with "LONDON FILM" superimposed over top, as well as a list of directors involved in the company.
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Korda, Alexander, Sir, 1893-1956 -- Correspondence; Kaye, Margaret, 1912-2002 -- Correspondence
- James Laver letter to Evelyn Hunt, 1937 October 2; Laver, James, 1899-1975; 1 sheet (1 page): autograph letter, signed; 12 x 19 cm (Box 1, Folder 40)
  Laver says he will gladly give a prize for "best theatrical costume" and asks about the exact amount.
  Letterhead: "Victoria & Albert museum, South Kensington, S.W.7." Also "National Scheme for Disabled Men" stamp
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Laver, James, 1899-1975 -- Correspondence; Hunt, Evelyn Janet, 1914-2001 -- Correspondence
- James Laver letter to Evelyn Hunt, 1937 November 13; Laver, James, 1899-1975; 1 sheet (1 page): typed letter, signed; 24 x 19 cm (Box 1, Folder 41)
  Laver confirms a time to see the exhibit with Hunt.
  Letterhead: "Department of Engraving, Illustration, & Design, Victoria & Albert Museum, South Kensington, London, S.W.7." Also "National Scheme for Disabled Men" stamp
- Printed invitation to James Laver, 1 card: 12 x 16 cm (Box 1, Folder 42)
  Printed invitation to Sketch Club Exhibition, "by P. Wyndham Lewis," with "James Laver Esq. & Friends" written in invitee field. Marginalia in pencil on back, various names matched with positions including secretary, chair, and treasurer; most unclear.
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Laver, James, 1899-1975 -- Correspondence; Lewis, Wyndham, 1882-1957
- Vivien Lawson letter to Joseph Jago, 1934 July 20; Lawson, Vivien; 1 folded sheet (4 pages): autograph letter, signed; 16 x 23 cm, folded to 16 x 12 cm (Box 1, Folder 43)
  Lawson says she is "always glad to do anything for the R.C.A Sketch Club" and offers one guinea, to use however the Committee wants, with a preference that a prize go to someone who hasn't received one. In a different hand at the bottom is written: "stout [?] fella". Also includes five graphite sketches of faces.
  Correspondence; Graphite drawings; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Lawson, Vivien -- Correspondence; Jago, Joseph -- Correspondence
- P. Wyndham Lewis letter to Frank B. Mason, 1934 July 17; Lewis, Wyndham, 1882-1957; 1 sheet (1 page): autograph letter, signed; 26 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 44)
  Lewis accepts Mason's invitation to officiate at the opening of the exhibition, and asks that "before the time comes for doing my stuff you must explain the ritual to me of course!" He proposes further discussions and includes an address.
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Lewis, Wyndham, 1882-1957 -- Correspondence; Mason, Frank B. -- Correspondence
- Eric Maclagan letter to Frank B. Mason, 1934 December 19; Maclagan, Eric Robert Dalrymple, 1879-1951; 1 sheet (1 page): typed letter, signed; 24 x 19 cm (Box 1, Folder 45)
  Maclagan thanks Mason for his letter, and says the museum is always glad to assist the students of the RCA.
  Letterhead: "Victoria & Albert Museum, South Kensington, London, S.W.7." with National Scheme for Disabled Men stamp
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Maclagan, Eric Robert Dalrymple, 1879-1951 -- Correspondence; Mason, Frank B. -- Correspondence; Victoria and Albert Museum
- Eric Maclagan letter to J. Anthony Denney, 1935 June 28; Maclagan, Eric Robert Dalrymple, 1879-1951; 1 sheet (2 pages): typed letter, signed; 24 x 19 cm (Box 1, Folder 46)
  Maclagan gives details of when the Students' Group may use space in the Victoria and Albert Museum, and provides conditions for the use of the space, namely that no work or responsibilities fall on museum staff; that work and showings happen during museum hours; and that sale of art is not permitted. He asks for the exact dates of the exhibition.
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Maclagan, Eric Robert Dalrymple, 1879-1951 -- Correspondence; Denney, Anthony, 1913-1990 -- Correspondence; Victoria and Albert Museum
- Eric Maclagan letter to Margaret Kaye, 1937 July 3; Maclagan, Eric Robert Dalrymple, 1879-1951; 1 sheet (1 page): typed letter, signed; 24 x 19 cm (Box 1, Folder 47)
  Maclagan gives details of when the Students' Group may use space in the Victoria and Albert Museum, and provides conditions for the use of the space, namely that no work or responsibilities fall on museum staff; that work and showings happen during museum hours; and that sale of art is not permitted.
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Maclagan, Eric Robert Dalrymple, 1879-1951 -- Correspondence; Kaye, Margaret, 1912-2002 -- Correspondence; Victoria and Albert Museum
- J. Young (secretary for Eric Maclagan) letter to Evelyn Hunt (?), 1937 November 4; Maclagan, Eric Robert Dalrymple, 1879-1951; 1 sheet (1 page): typed letter, signed; 25 x 20 cm (Box 1, Folder 48)
  Young conveys Maclagan's willingness to present a prize at the exhibition, as before.
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Maclagan, Eric Robert Dalrymple, 1879-1951 -- Correspondence; Hunt, Evelyn Janet, 1914-2001 -- Correspondence
- Reginald Herbert Marlow letter to J. Anthony Denney, 1935 July 15; Marlow, Reginald Herbert; 1 sheet (1 page): autograph letter, signed; 23 x 18 cm (Box 1, Folder 49)
  Marlow agrees to give a prize for ceramics, and encloses a check for that purpose.
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Marlow, Reginald Herbert -- Correspondence; Denney, Anthony, 1913-1990 -- Correspondence
- Reginald Herbert Marlow letter to Evelyn Hunt, 1937 October 3; Marlow, Reginald Herbert; 1 sheet (1 page): autograph letter, signed; 26 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 50)
  Marlow agrees to give a prize for pottery and encloses a check for one guinea.
  Letterhead: "Croydon School of Arts and Crafts"
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Marlow, Reginald Herbert -- Correspondence; Hunt, Evelyn Janet, 1914-2001 -- Correspondence
- Reginald Herbert Marlow letter to Evelyn Hunt, 1937 November 17; Marlow, Reginald Herbert; 1 sheet (1 page): autograph letter, signed; 26 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 51)
  Marlow thanks Hunt for the invitation to the exhibition opening and proposes a time to visit the show to select a winner of the prize.
- Naomi Mitchison letter to Evelyn Hunt, 1937 [?]; Mitchison, Naomi, 1897-1999; 1 sheet (1 page): autograph letter, signed; 18 x 12 cm (Box 1, Folder 52)
  Mitchison agrees to sponsor a prize this year (as she has before).
  Letterhead: "River Court, Hammersmith Mall, London.W.6. Telephone. Riverside 2267. Station. Ravenscourt Park 3 1/2 minutes."
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Mitchison, Naomi, 1897-1999 -- Correspondence; Hunt, Evelyn Janet, 1914-2001 -- Correspondence
- Walter Nugent Monck letter to Frank B. Mason, 1934 September 8; Monck, Walter Nugent Bligh, 1878-1958; 1 sheet (1 page): autograph letter, signed; 21 x 13 cm (Box 1, Folder 53)
  Monck agree to provide a prize, and proposes one for a set design for Shakespeare's Comedy of Errors or a set design for The Merchant of Venice.
  Letterhead: "The Maddermarket Theatre, Norwich (under the direction of Nugent Monck), Tel. Norwich 1360"
  Correspondence; Theaters -- Stage-setting and scenery; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Monck, Walter Nugent Bligh, 1878-1958 -- Correspondence; Mason, Frank B. -- Correspondence
- Walter Nugent Monck letter to Frank B. Mason, 1934 September 23; Monck, Walter Nugent Bligh, 1878-1958; 1 sheet (1 page): autograph letter, signed; 21 x 13 cm (Box 1, Folder 54)
  Monck regrets that he cannot attend the exhibition though suggests H. Vernon Gardner as an alternative judge. He includes his address, which is written again at the bottom of the letter, in pencil and in a different hand.
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Monck, Walter Nugent Bligh, 1878-1958 -- Correspondence; Mason, Frank B. -- Correspondence; Gardner, H. Vernon
- Walter Nugent Monck letter to J. Anthony Denney, 1935 July 9; Monck, Walter Nugent Bligh, 1878-1958; 1 sheet (1 page): autograph letter, signed; 26 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 55)
  Monck accepts Denney's invitation to sponsor another prize: "Last year I withheld my prize because none of the students had bothered to enter for the exact Shakespeare plays that I set. The object being that they should do as they are asked to do - as in life - not what they choose, which is seldom what is required of one. I will try once again. A set of designs for 'The Tempest' [...]."
  Letterhead includes large design of a bird on a column, alongside "The Norwich Players" and reads "The Norwich Players, Under the direction of Nugent Monck, Maddermarket Theatre, Norwich, Telephone No. 1360"
  Correspondence; Theaters -- Stage-setting and scenery; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Monck, Walter Nugent Bligh, 1878-1958 -- Correspondence; Denney, Anthony, 1913-1990 -- Correspondence
- B.L. Leary (secretary to Walter Nugent Monck) letter to unidentified recipient (probably J. Anthony Denney), 1935 August 16; Monck, Walter Nugent Bligh, 1878-1958; 1 sheet (1 page): typed letter, signed; 26 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 56)
  Leary says that Monck would be glad to attend the judging and opening of the exhibition if he is in London.
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Monck, Walter Nugent Bligh, 1878-1958 -- Correspondence; Denney, Anthony, 1913-1990 -- Correspondence
- Eleanor Robertson (secretary to Raymond Mortimer) letter to Evelyn Hunt, 1937 September 17; Mortimer, Raymond, 1895-1980; 1 sheet (1 page): typed letter, signed; 26 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 57)
  Robertson says that Mortimer is on holiday, but she will bring Hunt's letter to his attention when he returns.
  Letterhead: "The New Statesmen and Nation, The Weekend Review, 10 Great Turnstile, London, W.C.1, Holborn 3216"
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Mortimer, Raymond, 1895-1980 -- Correspondence; Hunt, Evelyn Janet, 1914-2001 -- Correspondence
- Raymond Mortimer letter to Evelyn Hunt, 1937 September 29; Mortimer, Raymond, 1895-1980; 1 sheet (1 page): autograph letter, signed; 26 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 58)
  Mortimer accepts Hunt's offer to adjudicate in the upcoming exhibition, "though I feel a certain shyness about it, as I am not a painter myself."
- Raymond Mortimer letter to Evelyn Hunt, 1937?; Mortimer, Raymond, 1895-1980; 1 sheet (1 page): autograph letter, signed; 13 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 59)
  Mortimer confirms a time to come see the paintings--"I want to see the paintings by daylight."
- John Nash letter to Frank B. Mason, 1934? July 22; Nash, John, 1893-1977; 1 sheet (1 page): autograph letter, signed; 22 x 18 cm (Box 1, Folder 60)
  Nash accepts the offer to judge at the exhibition and notes that he will be teaching at the Royal College of Art himself in October.
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Nash, John, 1893-1977 -- Correspondence; Mason, Frank B. -- Correspondence
- Fred P. Phillips letter to Frank B. Mason, 1934 July 13; Phillips, Fred P., 1880-; 1 sheet (1 page): typed letter, signed; 26 x 19 cm (Box 1, Folder 61)
  Phillips agrees to sponsor a prize as before, "the subject to be a Double Royal poster advertising ORIENT CRUISES to NORWAY or MEDITERRANEAN."
  Letterhead includes orange image of a castle, and "Sanders Phillips & Co. LTD, The Baynard Press, Chryssell Road, London, S.W.9"
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Phillips, Fred P., 1880- -- Correspondence; Mason, Frank B. -- Correspondence
- Fred P. Phillips letter to J. Anthony Denney, 1935 July 22; Phillips, Fred P., 1880-; 1 sheet (2 pages): typed letter, signed; 26 x 19 cm (Box 1, Folder 62)
  Phillips agrees to sponsor a prize as before, with the condition that it be withdrawn if less than twelve students submit. Marginalia on back.
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Phillips, Fred P., 1880- -- Correspondence; Denney, Anthony, 1913-1990 -- Correspondence
- G.R. Pope letter to Frank B. Mason (?), 1934 November 22; Pope, G. R.; 1 sheet (2 pages): typed letter, signed; 26 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 63)
  Pope enquires about whether the Sketch Club plans to advertise for their upcoming exhibition: "It is, I am sure, unnecessary to remind you that readers of the 'Morning Post' are mostly people with money to spend, and a fair amount of leisure." Unrelated marginalia on back.
  Letterhead: "The Morning Post, 15, Tudor Street, E.C.4, Telephone: Central 1500"
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Pope, G. R. -- Correspondence; Mason, Frank B. -- Correspondence
- Bernard Rackham letter to Evelyn Hunt, 1937 October 1; Rackham, Bernard, 1876-1964; 1 sheet (1 page): autograph letter, signed; 25 x 19 cm (Box 1, Folder 64)
  Rackham agrees to present a prize of one guinea.
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Rackham, Bernard, 1876-1964 -- Correspondence; Hunt, Evelyn Janet, 1914-2001 -- Correspondence
- Gwen Raverat letter to Evelyn Hunt, 1937?; Raverat, Gwen, 1885-1957; 1 sheet (1 page): autograph letter, signed; 18 x 11 cm (Box 1, Folder 65)
  Raverat cannot make it to London to see the show on the day suggested--she suggests another time.
  Letterhead: "Harlton Near Cambridge, Telephone Harston 274"
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Raverat, Gwen, 1885-1957 -- Correspondence; Hunt, Evelyn Janet, 1914-2001 -- Correspondence
- Gwen Raverat letter to Evelyn Hunt, 1937?; Raverat, Gwen, 1885-1957; 1 sheet (2 pages): autograph letter, signed; 18 x 12 cm (Box 1, Folder 66)
  Raverat agrees to give a guinea as a prize, though "it is not a precedent for ever!" She also agrees to come to see the show to pick a winner for the prize.
- Herbert Read letter to J. Anthony Denney, 1934 November 13; Read, Herbert, 1893-1968; 1 sheet (1 page): typed letter, signed; 26 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 67)
  Read writes to let Denney know he is ill, and will likely not be able to fulfill his role for the exhibition, though he discusses the possibility of postponement.
  Letterhead: "3 The Mall Parkhill Road London NW3"
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Read, Herbert, 1893-1968 -- Correspondence; Denney, Anthony, 1913-1990 -- Correspondence
- Herbert Read letter to J. Anthony Denney, 1935 July 30; Read, Herbert, 1893-1968; 1 sheet (1 page): typed letter, signed; 26 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 68)
  Read accepts the invitation to act as adjudicator for a prize at the exhibition.
- Herbert Read letter to Evelyn Hunt, 1937 October 14; Read, Herbert, 1893-1968; 1 sheet (1 page): typed letter, signed; 26 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 69)
  Read explains he has no knowledge of photography, and that he thinks Hunt should find another candidate to judge at the exhibit, though he agrees to serve if she can find no one else.
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Read, Herbert, 1893-1968 -- Correspondence; Hunt, Evelyn Janet, 1914-2001 -- Correspondence
- Edward Robinson letter to Margaret Kaye (?), 1936 August 20; Robinson, Edward G., 1893-1973; 2 sheets (2 pages): typed letters, signed; 26 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 70)
  Robinson's secretary, in a cover letter, apologizes for a letter which "went astray in the post." A copy of that letter is enclosed--in it, Robison regrets he will be back in America at the time of the exhibition.
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Robinson, Edward G., 1893-1973 -- Correspondence; Kaye, Margaret, 1912-2002 -- Correspondence
- William Rothenstein letter to Evelyn Hunt, 1937 October 3; Rothenstein, William, 1872-1945; 1 sheet (1 page): autograph letter, signed; 14 x 18 cm (Box 1, Folder 71)
  Rothenstein offers a prize of one guinea to the best "satirical composition" in the show.
  Letterhead: "High Point, Highgate Village, N.6. Mountview 2332"
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Rothenstein, William, 1872-1945 -- Correspondence; Hunt, Evelyn Janet, 1914-2001 -- Correspondence
- William Rothenstein postcard to Evelyn Hunt, 1937 November 11; Rothenstein, William, 1872-1945; 1 postcard: autograph postcard, signed; 10 x 16 cm (Box 1, Folder 72)
  Rothenstein says he will try to make it to the show at the suggested date, if not, later.
  Letterhead: "From Sir William Rothenstein, High Point, Highgate Village, N.6., Telephone: Mountview 2332"
- Albert Rutherston letter to Joseph Jago, 1934 October 10; Rutherston, Albert, 1881-1953; 1 sheet (1 page): autograph letter, signed; 17 x 14 cm (Box 1, Folder 73)
  Rutherston encloses a check, and discusses seeing the show.
  Blind-embossed letterhead: "Nash End Cottage Bisley on Stround [?] Gloucestershire, Tel. Bisley 22"
  Correspondence; Royal College of Art (Great Britain). Sketch Club; Rutherston, Albert, 1881-1953 -- Correspondence; Jago, Joseph -- Correspondence
- Albert Rutherston letter to unidentified recipient, Rutherston, Albert, 1881-1953; 1 sheet (1 page): typed letter, signed; 21 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 74)
  Rutherston encloses a check and discusses possible times to come judge his portion of the show. He further asks that he might no longer be included on the list of prize givers, as he feels he should devote any money to his own students.
  Top of letter is torn off.